The very first thing you'll
要实现一个粒子滤波器
need to do to implement a particle filter is initialize
你要做的第一件事情就是初始化
all your particles.
所有粒子
You'll have to decide how many particles you want to use.
你必须决定要使用的粒子数量
This parameter is mostly decided empirically,
这个参数大多数情况下是按经验确定的
but theoretically, the particle filter
但从理论上说 粒子滤波器
will exactly represent the Bayesian posterior distribution
会在粒子数量接近无限大时
as the number of particles approaches infinity.
准确地呈现贝叶斯后验分布
If you have too few particles, you
如果粒子数量太少
will not have enough to cover all of the high likelihood
则不够覆盖所有高可能性位置
positions, so you might miss the correct position.
因此可能漏掉准确位置
For instance, if each cell in this grid
例如 如果这个网格里的所有单元格
is equally likely to be the car's position,
是车辆所处位置的可能性均等
and you only have three particles,
而你只有三个粒子
you wouldn't have enough particles right now
那么 粒子数量就不足以表达
to represent this.
这个概率
However, having too many particles
但是 粒子数量太多
will slow down your filter, and prevent it
会拖慢你的滤波器 并阻止它
from localizing a self-driving car in real time.
实时定位无人驾驶车
There are two main ways you can initialize your particles.
粒子初始化有两种主要方式
The first is to sample uniformly across the state space.
首先 在状态空间里均匀取样
For instance, you could divide the state space into a grid,
例如 你可以把状态空间划分成一个网格
and put one particle in each cell.
在每个单元格中放置一个粒子
However, this approach is not very practical
但是 这种方法有局限性
if the state space is too large, such as in the case
不适用于状态空间太大的情况 例如
of a self-driving car, where the state
无人驾驶车的状态空间跨度
space spans essentially the entire land
很大 可以包括整个
surface of the earth.
地球表面
The second approach for initialization
第二种初始化方法
is to sample around some kind of initial estimate.
是在某个初始估算值周围取样
For a self-driving car, this initial estimate
对无人驾驶车 初始估算值
can come from a global positioning system, or GPS.
可能来自全球定位系统 GPS
If you remember from the very beginning of the localization
在定位课程刚开始的时候
module, you cannot rely on GPS alone for localization,
我们说过 不能单独依赖 GPS 进行定位
because of its low accuracy and reduced availability in certain
因为它准确度低 在某些环境下可用性
environments.
受限
However, GPS can be very useful to provide
但是 GPS 在提供粗略的初始位置估算方面
initial rough estimate of your location.
非常有用
For implementation in the particle filter project,
如果要在粒子滤波器实战项目中实现初始化
I want you to initialize your particle filter
我希望你能从高斯分布中取样
by sampling from a Gaussian distribution,
从而初始化你的粒子滤波器
Taking into account Gaussian sensor noise
同时考虑到初始 GPS 位置估算
around the initial GPS position estimate,
的高斯传感器噪声
and the initial heading estimate.
和初始航向估算
Now, I want you to practice doing this in C++ by using
下面 你需要在 C++ 中练习操作
the C++ standard library, normal distribution function to sample
使用 C++ 标准库、正态分布函数
positions around a GPS measurement.
在一个 GPS 测量值周围进行位置取样